We are talking about transparency for the client.
We are trying to understand that clause.
So are we
unethical?  What you said next is having a
huge impact on our
personal image.  Further you are saying
however some surplus entities means we are some
surplus entities for you.  People who are
trying to develop ethical practices in the industry.
Talking about transparency.  But
why did it take you 7 months to plan?  Did
you not receive any official replies through mail
?  Didn't receive your mail?   Were
n't you given continuous reminders
?  Who gives you the right?  Why did Transforming 360 suddenly stop selling and promoting that amazing product of such a
favorite health insurance company on March 10, 2025
?  Today in this video we will
understand each and every thing.  And after 7 months,
ICCL LBD today gives a reply which
raises questions on our ethical
approach which is
not acceptable to us at all.  So today in this video,
many amazing things will be
decoded transparently in front of you and that
reply will also be explained which today after 7 months,
after many follow ups, after
encouraging multiple platforms,
finally that reply has come and
in that reply some such terms have been used
which are
not acceptable to us at all.  Around March 10th,
we fully understood the product.
When we looked at the policy wording in depth,
we found a hidden clause
and that was material change.  Material change was
a hidden clause that was very risky for the customer.
Such a clause which
gave the company the right that if there were
any new changes in the medical history at the time of renewal in future,
then it was
mandatory to inform the company and the company would
decide the premiums and the scope of
cover.  So this was a condition that
shook us to the core.  And after understanding it thoroughly and
understanding the terms and conditions of many companies,
exactly after 7 days we again mailed
our ICIC LBA manager and
asked for justification there.
Phone communication continued continuously.  It kept being said
that you should work.  You will definitely get this reply.
Such a condition does not mean this, it is not like
that.  But ultimately,
if you are seeing that condition on the screen in front of you today, then
what do you understand about it?  So
please comment in the comment section and tell us
whether this condition
was justified or not for a common man.  One of the most
favorite organization ICC Lumbard for
us.  And we respect it so much
because this organization has
given some great leaders to the industry.  And
if one system one ethics is taking root somewhere in the industry today, then it is the
contribution of this company, which we also appreciate.
But ultimately when it comes to customers, it is
very important for us to look at customer favor.
Because our base is totally
transparent.  And maintaining this transparency,
if you watch any of our
videos, you will see that we
always talk about what you will not get instead of
what you will get.  Taking this forward,
when this communication continued and this
continuous communication reached the National Head,
we did not receive any reply.  We have
not done a single Elevate or any ICICI Lum health insurance sale in the last seven months.
But finally, when we brought this thing to the fore on this platform a
month and a half ago, which the
company is calling a hero today, then
we have
all the evidence as to when we started this
and which platforms we touched to bring about
this change.  Finally when
Besha posted a video and
we commented on that video and asked him, boss please tell us what about
the material change.  So the
discussion starts from there.  So the
intention behind doing all this was that
ultimately this change should come so that
things can be corrected positively in customer's favour
and today I am happy that
these things have been corrected on 18th October.  But the
justification given by the company
and the way you have manipulated the words is
not acceptable to us at all.  You have clearly
said that of course
everything has been clarified with the organization and it has
no impact on the claim.
My dear, first of all I want to make it clear to you
that claims and material
change have nothing to do with each other.  Let
us once again understand your definition of material change.  It is
clearly written there that
if there is any change in your health status at the time of renewal, then it
is very important for you to inform the company and
then the company will decide your premium
or scope of cover, which means that it is very clear
and understandable that
premium loading can be charged on you.  And
secondly, the scope can also be reduced in the scope of cover.  This
means that if your sum
insured today is unlimited sum insured or Rs 1
crore, then it can also be reduced.
If you have developed any critical health problem.
So today you are talking about the fact that
till date there has been no impact of Lombard on this claim.
So we have
no tension regarding the claim.  Because your claim is very
amazing.  Here we are talking about material change.
So if we reply strictly on that, it would be
very good.
Because if we look at the guidelines of IRD, then there is a
clear guideline of IRD that
you cannot make any alteration on renewal.
Meaning that you cannot refuse anyone's renewal.
First of all, you cannot reduce anyone's sum
insured.  Secondly,
thirdly, you cannot charge any loading until finally
he is declaring his sum insured
and
loading can be levied on the increased sum insured because
that is treated as a fresh one but when it comes
to the point of renewal of renewing
the policy with the same sum insured, then you cannot do this, so was there a
need to bring in such a condition and
why did you have this condition in every policy
and why did you remain silent for 7 months.
Even after so many follow ups.  And
I do appreciate the National Head of ICC LBA
who had also replied this thing through mail a few months ago
that we will make these changes
and this condition is actually
not favourable.  So this condition should change.
So this condition has changed today.  We are very
happy about this.  Because
for millions and crores of people.  There
are a lot of benefits.  Doors have opened
for us too to work in a company where
we know that the claims are amazing and
the services are truly great.  But it is
very important to talk about that reply today.  Those who
want to maintain this transparency.  Today you
address them with a term that is
unethical.  Who gives you the right?
Who has given you such rights?  I would like to ask you
that I would also like to talk to you on legal terms.
You please prove to me
what unethical education we have done or what unethical
sales we have made.  So I would like the
justification.  So I would like to read out
your entire reply which
our manager sent to us in PDF form on 18th
October.  So let us
understand the clarification on the
material change clause in health policies.
Dear Partner, You may have come across recent
discussions on online platforms and a
few media outlets regarding the
material change clause in our health
insurance products Elevate and Health
Advantage.  Some of this post has led to
misrepresentation and it is important that
our valued partners like you and
customers have complete clarity on this
matter.  Here are a few important
points to note.  The Material Change Clause and
the Renewal Clause in our health policies,
when read together, are fully aligned and
customer friendly.  Both these conditions are
also shown separately on your screen.
You decide for yourself whether this
was really customer friendly.  This clause
primarily exists to reward health
improvement.  Here we are talking about
health improvement rewards.  If these were
truly health improvement rewards,
why was this condition labeled material change?  And where is it written there
that your premium will be reduced there.
And what does scope of cover mean?
Now clarification is given here.  For
example, if a policy holder improves their
health, we may remove earlier loadings
at renewal where ever possible.  It is being said here
that the loading will be removed at the
time of renewal.  So you should have clarified this thing
in the loading clause.
How are you manipulating this thing here
?  I don't know this
kind of justification is not acceptable
with the great company.  The second thing you can
talk about here is sharing health details, allowing us to
offer preventive health programs like
free checkups and wellness support.
What does material change have to do with the free
health checkups and wellness programs you will offer?
So I would like to understand this.
No fresh underwriting and medical
tests are required at renewal unless there is an
increase in sumshard it should be like this.
Edition of New Members
Understood Edition of Optional Cover Understood.
But here fresh underwriting and medical
test are required.  We have
not even talked about medical test nor does
your clause say so.  The discussion here is about the
scope of cover and premium.   Let's move ahead.
At ICC LBA no claim has ever been
rejected due to the material
change clause.  When did we say this and which
platform has said such a thing?  Please
provide that video and that evidence so that
things become more transparent.
Now comes the thing which is feeling very
problematic for us and which
is not at all respectable for me
and not at all acceptable for me.
So what is ICICI LBA trying to say
?  Due to the Material Change Clause, a
policyholder's premium and coverage will not be
altered if they develop a new disease or
condition after policy issuance. We are fully
compliant with IRDA regulations and our
policy terms follow standard industry
practices.  That's truly amazing.  But
why did it take you 7 months to finally do it?  Did
you not receive any official replies through mail
?  Didn't receive your mail?   Were
n't you given continuous reminders
?  I just want to understand.  But
now comes the main issue where you
called us unethical advisors.
Here I want to understand that thing and your entire
reply.
I will read it out in front of the entire public
and please you all decide whether
we are talking about transparency for the client.
We are
trying to understand that clause.  So are
we unethical?  Please try to
understand follow me.  While we have already addressed this matter
with the course team
regarding the linkage between the material
change clause and the renewal clause in our
policy terms.  However, what is being discussed here is that till now the
team of Bezak has
brought these things to the fore and they have
discussed with the team of Bezak that there is no such
problem and I am
also giving you this evidence, you will see in front of the screen that
we have commented on the videos of Bezak
regarding the material change, only then this
matter has gone forward through Bezak.  We do
n't want any reward for this here.  We do
n't want any appreciation here.  But the
question is
how much impactful what you said next is having on our
personal image.  Further you are saying however some
unsurplus entities means we are sun
unsurplus entities for you.  People who are
trying to develop ethical practices in the industry.
Talking about transparency.  You have been given a
completely transparent business.  You do
n't scrutinize our entire business and find even a single unethical practice
anywhere.  You cancel our license.
Now let's move ahead.  Unsurplus
entities and individuals have been
referencing it with these accurate
interpretations.  So let me repeat this line
that is so painful for us
and that is how ever some
unsurplus entities and individuals have been
referencing it with inaccurate
interpretations.   I just want
to understand which
inaccurate decision we made.  We never talked about the possibility of
you facing any problem with the claim.  We have
not even mentioned here that your sum
insured will not be increased.  The
only thing that is happening here is what is your material
change saying?  Your material change clearly
states that at the time of renewal,
it is the responsibility of the customer
and advisor to declare if there are
any changes in your medical records.  So the company
decides the scope of cover and end premium.
Meaning that it can do both things and
can also do one of these two things.  Please
answer this to us.  How you can call
us surplus entities.  I just want to
understand.  Please do
tell us what mistake we made, if
we asked this, highlighted this
and why it took you 7 months to
reply to this.  You are such an amazing
company.  We believe in ICC LBA wholeheartedly.
Because ICICI LBA has
given very good standards to the industry.  I am not
against the company, not at all.  But I am
standing with the customers because I am an
intermediary when we are claiming that the
transparency is our base is our
foundation.  I have to value this and we
value this thing from the core.  And
whenever we contact any customer, many of you will be
our customers who have already
taken a policy from us.  Either health
insurance or term insurance or
disability insurance or home insurance
or all of these products.  So
please do comment in the comment section and tell us
how you have seen our practices.  Have
you ever seen
someone do underwriting in such a transparent manner
?  When we educate people about policy,
we never talk about features.
We always talk about terms and
conditions.  What will not be available?  If I get it, then on
what conditions will I get it?  How much percentage will
I get?  And the customer is made to declare each and every thing
starting from birth till
date.  So are such
tags suitable for us for these things?  So I just want to
understand this.  So you can
make anyone a hero.  We have no problem.
But we cannot accept this tag of
surplus entities.  Please behave
responsibly.  I request once again that you are
truly respectful to us.  But please,
you cannot counter our respect in this manner.  To
make your image positive.
You brought this change.  I am truly truly
appreciating you from the core of
my heart.  I am thankful.  And
even before this, there are many changes for which I
fought a lot.  Even when I was an employee,
you can refer for internal congenital disease.
You can pick up the entire old policy statement and
see it.  Till 2014-15-16, only Star
Health Insurance and New India
Insurance covered it
after a waiting period of two years and for all other
companies it was a permanent exclusion.
We had highlighted this thing so much
and Apollo Mechanic was the first company
after the two companies that they also
brought it on a waiting period of two years and
today every company is following it.
So is it the job of non-surplus entities to bring about such changes
?  So, I'm
really upset with this kind of
language.  Whatever you have used, please remove it
immediately.  So, I request every viewer
whether such words of LMB
are correct or it is wrong for us to
ask questions in this manner in favor of customers.
So please do let us know by commenting.   Please
share this video as much as possible
and I am saying it again that ICC
Labord is one of the greatest organization
in this insurance space but the kind of
language, whoever has done this, I want the
written apology from you and not in my favor but
whoever has highlighted those things has done it in
favor of the clients.  If you have made a mistake,
you can address it positively.
Please do not challenge anyone's
vision or his mission
or his emotions or his hardship by saying such words to him
and we hope
that we will move forward with a very good association
and we will be able to promote health insurance to those people in India where
still more than 70% of the people are uninsured.
But ultimately this video is
not against any company.  I am
not against any product.  This video is solely
and solely against that communication.  So
I request each one of you to please watch this video
once again after revising it.   Let's
look at each fact.  Each screenshot will be
attached to it.  You should check everything and
then give a genuine reply.
And I also request every customer
who has bought
health insurance,
term insurance, disability and any
insurance product through our platform.  So
please do submit your feedback here.
Genuine Feedbacks Only.
Thank you so much.  And we will meet soon with a new
video and we will decode such
hidden terms and conditions and I request each
one of you that always do not shy away from calling right as right and wrong as
wrong, only then will a change
come because we cannot bring about change alone.
We all have to bring about change together.   The
employees sitting inside the insurance company
also have to address every matter positively.
We are the ones who have
also taken a lot of actions against fraudulent claims.
Companies have always been educated.
Always made aware.  Have communicated.
Those hospitals have been
promoted to be removed from the system.  So please
such words are not acceptable to me at all.
I request you please remove
Sach Communications.  Because it is not causing any problem to my image.
This also challenges your mindset and
your positive image somewhere
that your reply itself is
not fitting into a frame.  Because
material change is saying something else and your
communication is talking about claim.  Whereas
both of them are not linked to each other.   The
issue here is the future of your sum insured.
Because till now we used to understand
that features in health insurance can be
removed because the company has the product modification clause,
product withdrawal clause.
But some insured was something that
continuity would always remain in renewal.
But this clause was challenging that thing also.
So this question was very valid.  There
may be some problem in my knowledge.
We may not understand.  So
why are you replying to this thing in 7 months
?  Please clarify this thing a little
so that
you can bring more transparency.  Thank you so much
everyone.  Stay connected, stay
progressive.